

///====== questions array===========//
var questions = [
    {
        id:"1",
        question: "Which of the following is the correct syntax to print a page using JavaScript?",
        answer: "window.print();",
        options:[
            "window.print();",
            " browser.print();",
            "navigator.print();",
            "document.print();"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"2",
        question: "Which built-in method returns the calling string value converted to lower case?",
        answer:  "toLowerCase()",
        options:[
            "toLowerCase()",
            "toLower()",
            "changeCase(case)",
            "None of the above."
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"3",
        question: "Which of the following is not a web browser",
        answer: "Facebook",
        options:[
            "MOSAIC",
            "WWW",
            "Facebook",
            "Netscape navigator"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"4",
        question: "Which one of the followings is a programming language",
        answer: "HTML",
        options:[
            "HTTP",
            "HTML",
            "HPML",
            "FTP"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"5",
        question: "Which protocol is used to received e-mail",
        answer: "SMPT",
        options:[
            "SMTP",
            "POP3",
            "SMPT",
            "SSH"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"6",
        question: "In which year '@' sign was first chosen for its use in e-mail address",
        answer: "1972",
        options:[
            "1972",
            "1960",
            "1985",
            "1975"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"7",
        question: "A folder in windows computer can't be made with the name",
        answer: "CON",
        options:[
            "CAN",
            "CON",
            "MAK",
            "MAKE"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"8",
        question: "What is the extension type of the excel 2007 files",
        answer: ".xlsx",
        options:[
            ".xls",
            ".xlsx",
            ".xsl",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"9",
        question: "The basic units of a excel spreedsheet where we enter data is called",
        answer: "CELL",
        options:[
            "TAB",
            "CELL",
            "BOX",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"10",
        question: "The maximum number of rows supported by Excel 2003 spreadsheet is",
        answer: "65,536",
        options:[
            "10,000",
            "35,356",
            "55,782",
            "65,536"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"11",
        question: "The maximum number of rows supported by Excel 2007 spreadsheet is",
        answer: "10,48,576",
        options:[
            "9,68,576",
            "12,15,857",
            "13,42,554",
            "10,48,576"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"12",
        question: "Which one is a 'text editor' for Microsoft Windows",
        answer: "Notepad",
        options:[
            "MS Word",
            "Ms Excel",
            "WordPad",
            "Notepad"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"13",
        question: "Web pages are written using ?",
        answer: "HTML",
        options:[
            "FTP",
            "HTTP",
            "URL",
            "HTML"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"14",
        question: "Indiaâ€™s first super computer is ?",
        answer: "Param",
        options:[
            "Agni",
            "Flow solver",
            "Trisul",
            "Param"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"15",
        question: "Which of the following is NOT operating system ?",
        answer: "Java",
        options:[
            "Dos",
            "Unix",
            "Window NT",
            "Java"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"16",
        question: "One byte is equivalent to ?",
        answer: "8 bits",
        options:[
            "4 bits",
            "8 bits",
            "32 bits",
            "12 bits"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"17",
        question: "What is the full form of lP ?",
        answer: "Internet protocol",
        options:[
            "Interface program",
            "Interface protocol",
            "Internet protocol",
            "Internet program"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"18",
        question: "A terabyte comprises ?",
        answer: "1024 gigabyte",
        options:[
            "1024 kilobyte",
            "1024 gigabyte",
            "1024 megabyte",
            "1024 byte"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"19",
        question: "The most widely used computer device is",
        answer: "Internal hard disk",
        options:[
            "Solid state disks",
            "Solid state disks",
            "Internal hard disk",
            "Mouse"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"20",
        question: "How many recent files you can display on File menu at maximum?",
        answer: "9",
        options:[
            "3",
            "7",
            "9",
            "12"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"21",
        question: "What is the maximum size of a word document created",
        answer: "32 MB",
        options:[
            "1 MB",
            "32 MB",
            "16MB",
            "999KB"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"22",
        question: "How many layers in the TCP/IP protocol layers",
        answer: "4",
        options:[
            "7",
            "5",
            "12",
            "4"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"23",
        question: "Total number of function keys in a computer keyboard",
        answer: "12",
        options:[
            "10",
            "12",
            "14",
            "8"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"24",
        question: "Linux' is an example of",
        answer: "Operating System",
        options:[
            "Software",
            "Application",
            "Operating System",
            "Browser"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"25",
        question: "Which key combination is used to permantly delete a file or folder",
        answer: "Shift+delete",
        options:[
            "Shift+delete",
            "Alt+delete",
            "CTRL+delete",
            "Delete"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"26",
        question: "Who programmed the first computer game 'Spacewar!' in 1962",
        answer: "Steave Russell",
        options:[
            "Steave Russell",
            "Konard Zuse",
            "Alan Emtage",
            "Tim Berners-Lee"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"27",
        question: "Who is known as the father of supercomputing",
        answer:  "Seymour Cray",
        options:[
            "David J. Brown",
            "Gene Amdahl",
            "Adam Dunkels",
            "Seymour Cray"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"28",
        question: "Who created the C programming Language",
        answer: "Dennis Ritchie",
        options:[
            "Ken Thompson",
            "Dennis Ritchie",
            "Robin Milner",
            "Frieder Nake"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"29",
        question: "Which one of the followings is a programming language",
        answer: "HTML",
        options:[
            "HTTP",
            "HTML",
            "HPML",
            "FTP"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"30",
        question: "Who is known as the father of internet",
        answer: "Vint Cerf",
        options:[
            "Alan Perlis",
            "Jean E. Sammet",
            "Vint Cerf",
            "Steve Lawrence"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"31",
        question: "Which one is the first high level programming language",
        answer: "FORTRAN",
        options:[
            "C",
            "COBEL",
            "FORTRAN",
            "C++"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"32",
        question: "Which one is the first word processor application",
        answer: "WordStar",
        options:[
            "MS Word",
            "Apple i Work",
            "Sun StarOffice",
            "WordStar"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"33",
        question: "Which one is the current fastest Supercomputer in India",
        answer: "SahasraT",
        options:[
            "Aaditya",
            "SAGA-220",
            "SahasraT",
            "HP Apollo 6000"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"34",
        question: "Which one is volatile memory in a computer system",
        answer: "RAM",
        options:[
            "HardDisk",
            "RAM",
            "ROM",
            "Optical Drive"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"35",
        question: "Which operating system is developed and used by Apple Inc",
        answer: "iOS",
        options:[
            "Windows",
            "Android",
            "iOS",
            "UNIX"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"36",
        question: "Who is the founder of Bluetooth",
        answer: "Ericsson",
        options:[
            "Ericsson",
            "IBM",
            "Apple",
            "Dell"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"37",
        question: "From which toolbar can we change chart type",
        answer: "Chart toolbar",
        options:[
            "Formatting toolbar",
            "Chart toolbar",
            "Formula bar",
            "Clipboard bar"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"38",
        question: "ASCII has how many codes",
        answer: "128",
        options:[
            "64",
            "128",
            "256",
            "382"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"39",
        question: "You can activate a cell in MS-Excel by",
        answer: "All of these",
        options:[
            "Pressing the Tab Key ",
            "Clicking the Cell",
            "Pressing an Arrow Key",
            "All of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"40",
        question: "Which of the following is not valid data type in MS-Excel",
        answer: "Character",
        options:[
            "Number",
            "Character",
            "Label",
            "Date/Time"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"41",
        question: "In context of Computers, FAT stands for",
        answer: "File Allocation Table",
        options:[
            "Folder Access Table",
            "File Access Table",
            "File Allocation Table",
            "Folder Allocation Table"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"42",
        question: "The ____________ protect systems from hackers",
        answer: "Firewall",
        options:[
            "Antivirus",
            "Backup",
            "Hard disk",
            "Firewall"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"43",
        question: "Errors in computer programmes are called",
        answer: "Bugs",
        options:[
            "Follies",
            "Mistake",
            "Bugs",
            "Spam"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"44",
        question: "Who is known as the Father of SMS",
        answer: "Matti Makkonen",
        options:[
            "Samir Bhatia",
            "Anuj Gupta",
            "Matti Makkonen",
            "Thomas Kurian"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"45",
        question: "When a computer suddenly stops working, it is said to be",
        answer: "Hanged",
        options:[
            "Crashed",
            "Bugged",
            "Hanged",
            "Held up"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"46",
        question: "A computer cannot boot if it does not have the",
        answer: "Operating System",
        options:[
            "Compiler",
            "Loader",
            "Assembler",
            "Operating System"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"47",
        question: "Magnetic disc is an example of",
        answer: "Offline storage",
        options:[
            "Online storage",
            "Offline storage",
            "Offset storage",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"48",
        question: "Caches are usually built out of",
        answer: "SRAMS",
        options:[
            "SRAMS",
            "DRAMS",
            "PROM",
            "EEPROM"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"49",
        question: "Virus is a computer __________ ",
        answer: "Program",
        options:[
            "File",
            "Database",
            "Network",
            "Program"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"50",
        question: "Which of the following is used to store large amount of data",
        answer: "Auxiliary storage",
        options:[
            "Primary memory",
            "Auxiliary storage",
            "Cache memory",
            "Random access memory"
        ]
    }
];







 
